<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>diaRy</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on diaRy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PDF table to data.frame</title>
      <link>/2019/02/08/pdf-table-to-data.frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/08/pdf-table-to-data.frame/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionI recently found myself needing to extract some tables from PDF format to some tabular format that I can manipulate in R. I needed to extract municipal population and GDP estimates from a document published by Statistics South Africa. Fortunately, the tabulizer package in R makes this task easier. The tabulizer package also depends on the rJava and tabulizerjars packages. I will start by loading these together with the tidyverse packages for data manipulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reapportion spatial overlaps between South African census boundaries: 2001 and 2011</title>
      <link>/2018/12/06/reapportion-spatial-overlaps-between-south-african-census-boundaries-2001-and-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/06/reapportion-spatial-overlaps-between-south-african-census-boundaries-2001-and-2011/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe documents accompanying the South African census of 2011 state that demarcations of geographical boundaries underwent a number of changes at provincial and municipal boundaries relative to those used for the 2001 census. This make it difficult to compare the 2011 census and the preceding census at this level. The aim of this exercise is to determine what proportion of the preceding census boundaries are included in the boundaries of the latest census.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:49:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Its me testing how o blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stata to R - BMI example</title>
      <link>/2017/03/24/stata-to-r---bmi-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/24/stata-to-r---bmi-example/</guid>
      <description>Note: This exercise is part of re-writing the SALDRU Stata course in R for DataFirst.Therefore, all descriptions, interpretation and logical approach comes from the original course and all I did is to write the R code.
IntroductionIn this exercise, we follow the BMI examples in the SALDRU Stata course. The exercise investigate determinants of BMI and in doing so address the following questions. What happens to your BMI as you get older?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>